Hey, this is Lance from Mangane. I want
to talk about skills, a new concept
introduced by Anthropic recently. Show
how I implemented them in our deep agent
CLI and then talk about the philosophy
behind skills and why they're
interesting. Now, this is a deep agency.
I've just spun this up in my terminal.
I'm going to ask the deep agent CLI to
perform web research on a topic. I'm
interested context engineering. It kicks
off. Now, you'll see something
interesting here. Based on my request,
it scanned its skills directory, which
I'll talk about in a minute, and it's
found a skill related to this topic of
web research, which I gave it. So, it
actually went ahead and read this
skill.md file, which gives a bunch of
context about how to perform web
research. So, you can think about skills
as like standard operating procedures
that you can give an agent for different
tasks. So, in this case, I've given the
deep agent CLI a number of different
skills, one of them for web research. So
what happens is when I ask this request
for research, it knows, hey, I have a
skill for that and it looks at a
particular file called skillmd in the
skills directory. It reads that file and
then it gathers a bunch of context about
this particular task that I wanted to
solve. The agent mentions it's going to
follow the web research workflow. Then
based upon the skill, it says, "Okay,
I'll follow that research workflow that
you've given me." creates a task list,
writes a request,
and it proceeds down this research
trajectory based upon the contents of
that skilled.md file, which it
dynamically loaded based upon my
request. So now what's happening is it's
going to kick off a sub agent per my
instructions to do research. We can see
that sub agent kicks off a bunch of web
searches. That's fine. I approve them
all. And you can run the deep agent CLI
in auto approve mode if you don't want
these human in the loop approval steps.
stage has conducted a bunch of research
and you can see it returns to me a nice
overview here. It's then checking its
to-do. Now it asked me for approval to
write the final report. That's great. So
I approve that. It's writing this file.
It's verifying completeness relative to
the request. So it reads this research
request.md which it wrote initially.
Verifies completeness and it finishes
the final report has been written to
this directory. I can enter bash mode
with the exclamation point. And I can
see the final report isn't written to my
directory along with the research
request. That's all great. And here's a
file. I can open it up. I can scan it.
So I get a very nicely researched rich
report with 17 citations on context
engineering. So you've seen skills in
action with our deep agent CLI. I want
to talk a little bit about the
philosophy behind skills and why I think
it's very interesting. So skills were
introduced by Enthropic recently. You
can see the very nice blog post on here.
Skills are nothing more than directory
of folders. Okay, each folder has a
particular skillmd file and the skillmd
file has a particular structure. It has
this YAML front matter and it has then
the rest of the instructions just as
markdown. Now the thing that's
interesting is this YAML front matter is
always loaded into the system prompt of
the agent. This is how it works with
cloud code. This is how we implemented
it with the deep agent CLI. So this YAML
front matter is a very very context
summary of what the skill does. If you
go to the deep agents repo, go to the
deep agent CLI folder, you see this
example subfolder, open it up, you'll
see skills and you can actually see the
skill. MD file for that web research
skill. Open that up and here you go. So
there's that YAML front matter. Very
nice. And then here is the full skill
and this outlines in detail how I want
the agent to conduct research. Now this
is just markdown. You can modify this in
any way you want. It just provides
instructions to the agent about how to
use it native tools to accomplish tasks.
Now, one of the important ideas here is
what Anthropic calls progressive
disclosure. So that basically means that
the YAML front matter is the only thing
pre-loaded in the system prompt. So
you're not overloading your agent with a
whole bunch of kind of lengthy skill
descriptions. You're only loading that
YAML front matter. The agent can see all
those and then decide, hey, if it wants
to use a skill, it's instructed then go
ahead and read this full skill MD file.
Now the skillmd just lives in a
directory and in the directory you can
have other files. You can have scripts
to run that can all just be explained in
the body of that skillmd file. Now
here's the key point. If you're using
cloud code for example cloud code is a
bunch of native tools for file access
using the shell and so it can read any
of these files. It can execute any
scripts using the bash tool. So using a
small set of native tools that can
implement whatever you specify in the
skillmd files, we've borrowed a lot of
those same ideas for the deep agent CLI.
We have a shell tool. We have file
manipulation tools. And so all you need
to do in the skillmd file is just say,
hey, what to do? Any scripts you want to
run, it can use this bash tool. Any
files you want to read, it can use it to
read file tool and so forth. So all
you're doing in the skillmd file is
you're providing context that the agent
can use using its native tools to do
stuff, execute scripts that live in the
folder, read files that live in the
folder, and so forth. Now, if we pull
back even a little bit further, why is
this interesting? Well, with agents, we
actually want agents to perform actions.
We want agents to be able to do things
in the world. That could be execute
code, that could be perform web search,
that could be other things. Now, we did
a webinar with Manis a few months ago
and they talked a lot about this action
space and how to design the action space
accordingly. And one of the principles
they talked about a lot is use a small
number of atomic tools at the function
calling layer or the tool calling layer
but give the agent access to a file
system where it can just run scripts if
it wants to perform additional actions.
This is a subtle but very interesting
point. So for example with manis just
like cloud code just like deep agent CLI
has a small number of native tools shell
tool file manipulation tools but it gave
but the agent has access to a whole
bunch of scripts that live inside in
that case it sandbox environment same
deal here with skill we're giving deep
agent cli or claw code access to a
directory of skills which can have
anything we want in it we could just
throw in scripts we could throw in files
and using the native shell tool as well
as file manipulation tools. The agent
can read these directories, poke through
them, run any scripts it wants. And this
is a way to expand the action space
significantly without loading up a whole
bunch of different functions. Now, let's
walk through this table. Why is that
interesting? Well, let's say we want the
agent to have five different actions. We
can load those all as independent
functions or tools. So, that means they
get bound to the model itself. And
typically what happens is when you bind
a tool to the model, you bind the full
tool description. And this can be quite
tokenheavy, particularly if you have
like say hundreds of tools. You're
binding all those tools as well as their
descriptions. Now with skills, the nice
thing is you're only supplying that YAML
front matter. It's a quick summary of
when to actually use the skill, which
really just means when to actually read
that full skill.mmd file to find out
what it's really all about and what to
do. So that YAML front matter really
provides the agent with a clue about
when to go ahead and execute the skill
by reading that full skill.mmd file.
Now, here's the thing that's really not.
If you bind a bunch of additional tools
to your model, could be via MCP, could
be via handrolled tools, you're bloating
up that tool calling space. So you think
about an agent has access to some number
of tools. It has to make a decision at
each turn about what tools to use. If
you bloat up that tool calling space, it
can get more confused. For example, you
can bind two different tools that are
very similar to the agent. It won't know
which one to call. This happens a lot.
People often talk about oh should I bind
what happens when I bind 20 tools 50
tools 100 tools to a model and some
people even flex that oh okay my agent
has 100 tools what you're seeing with
more state-of-the-art agents like
maniscloud code is actually small number
of tools less than 20 but give it access
to file system where it can just execute
where it can use its bash tool to
execute scripts if it needs to perform
additional actions. The point is that
skills are a nice way to expand the
action space of your agent without
actually bloating your function calling
layer, which is very important because
more functions mean more tokens and
function descriptions, but also more
cognitive load on the model itself. It
has to choose what tool to call at what
turn. The more tools you add, the more
potential for confusion. Now, what's the
catch here? Well, the catch is you need
access to a file system. So, there's a
very nice write up I link here from
Simon Willis talking about skills, and
he highlights that really as a critical
dependency, and I agree with that. that
I mean listen you need to give the agent
access to a computer and this is just a
quick diagram summarizing all that from
anthropic. So basically this is the
context window of the LM this represents
the agent system prompt and all these
YAML front matters loaded up from any
skills you give it. So this is this top
thing is all the agent will see when
it's deciding what skill to actually
call. So here's a request just like we
did perform web research. Here's an
example request. In this case, Claude
will say, "Okay, I'm aware of the
various skills that I have. It looks
like you want to do some PDF stuff.
Okay, I have a PDF skill. I'm going to
read in that skill. Cool." You can see
it uses this native bash tool to read
skill.md. Great. And then it's going to
use this bash tool to read some
additional file in that skill directory
based on the initial instructions and so
forth. So again, the idea is very simply
my agent has access to the skills
directory. You can use this native tools
to read in skills based on the user's
request. Now, if you look in the deep
agents read me, you can look in this
deep agent CLI folder. You can see we've
updated our read for the deep agent CLI
to include skills. And this is just one
implementation of skills. It's all open
source. You can inspect it if you want.
And of course, there's other ways to do
this. It follow exactly what we just
talked about from anthropic. You can
poke down here. You can see deep agents
is just easily installable like this.
Run it in your terminal just by calling
deep agents. And if you want to inspect
any skills, you can just run this
command deep agent skills list. Back in
my terminal, you can do that. And we can
see when I run that, I can see I have
these skills available. Project skills,
global skills, and it shows the paths
too. So the only difference is that
these global skills are available across
any project that I'm using deep agents
in. They live in your home directory in
deep agents. This is the default agent
I'm working with. The skills directory
and then the various skills folders.
That's all we have. Very nice. And in
this particular repo, I just have a test
skill that I've added. You can see this
is inside the deep agents repo and it's
a project level skill. So the YAML front
matter for all these skills at the
global level and the project level will
be loaded into the system prompt and the
agent can decide which ones it needs to
use. Again, we just saw it using this
web research skill. We asked for a
request related to web research and it
followed the instructions in this skills
directory and it followed the
instructions in the skills.mmd file in
this directory. If we want to see
another in action, let me ask a question
related to langraph. Create a langraph
agent. Save it to agent.py. So I've
added a skill called langraph docs. You
can see here's that skill.mmd. The yaml
front matter indicates use this skill
for any request related to langraph to
fetch relevant documentation to provide
accurate up-to-date guidance. Down here,
I basically give some instructions.
First, use your fetch URL tool. Again, a
built-in tool to the ad agent CLI. Read
our LMS.ext file. Reflect on the
request. Select a few different relevant
URLs from this lm.ext. text to read,
fetch them, and then use that to answer
the question. You can open up this
document and you can see there's just a
list of documentation URLs and some
little and a little bit of annotation
about what's in each one. So, we can go
back to our agent. You can see it read
that skill.mmd file. That's great. So,
it pulled in all those instructions.
Now, it wants to read that element.ext
file. That's great. I give it approval
there. It reads that and it's going to
it's going to reflect on that and then
choose to read a few different specific
documentation pages. That's fine. It's
going to read the quick start, the
overview. Good. I'll pull those in. It
read the documentation. Now it's
creating a file for me. This is cool.
Called agent.py. And I approve that.
Great. And it gives me a bunch of
instructions. And we're done. So skills
are a very easy way to expand the action
space of agents. The key dependencies
that you give your agent access to a
file system. The deep agent CLI has one
access to your local file system. So
that's great just like cloud code. And
two, it has a bunch of native tools
built in allowing it to run bash
commands, perform file manipulation,
fetch URLs and so forth. So with those
basic atomic tools, you can very easily
create skills by creating a skills
directory either at your global level or
project level. And in that directory,
just applying a skilled MD file properly
formatted, which tells the agent what
you want done. You can provide
additional files. You can provide
scripts and just give it instructions
simply in markdown about what to do and
it'll follow those instructions using it
native tools. Very simple concept, a
very nice way to expand the action space
of your agent and doesn't require the
complexities of tool calling. So
hopefully this is a useful overview for
skills and how they work and how we've
implemented them and how we built them
with the deep agent CLI. Thanks.