We've seen AI code enhancement
frameworks that massively elevate your
coding agents quality and efficiency
like GitHub spec kit, which is an open-
source toolkit that lets you focus on
product scenarios as well as predictable
outcomes instead of vibe coding every
piece from scratch. Then there's
OpenSpec. This is a lightweight
specdriven framework that does
everything specit does, but even better.
But both of these two frameworks were
inspired by BMAD, the breakthrough
method for agile AIdriven development.
BMAD is basically a mindset for building
AI features without chaos. It's a
repeatable playbook where you break
tasks into clear specs, constraints,
steps, and outcomes. So your AI behaves
like a disciplined engineer instead of
just five coders. EMAD isn't a framework
with APIs or templates. It's a method
that shapes how you think about AI
development. Specit and openspec just
implement the philosophy in code. BMAD
is the blueprint and the other two are
just power tools. In my opinion, BMAD is
a bit better because it fixes the
thinking behind AI development which is
going to make any tool or agent more
predictable, consistent, and scalable
rather than just giving your AI coding
agent a framework. The BMAD method uses
aensic planning to generate precise
consistent specs via specialized agents
and context engineered development to
turn those specs into fully detailed
stories for dev agents. This eliminates
planning gaps and context loss and it
makes AI development predictable and
reliable. To get started, use the link
in the description below and head over
to the BMAD Core GitHub repo. BMAD Core
is the foundation of all BMAD tools.
There's different modules that are used
within BMAD core which I'll explain in a
second, but BMAD core is essentially
just organizing all the specialized AI
agents as well as guided workflows to
make AI reliable, context aware and it's
a modular system that adapts to any
project size and it keeps customization
safe. It integrates with AI agents,
integrates with ideides and power tools
like BMAD method, the BMAD builder and
creative intelligence which are
different sorts of modules. These
separate modules are helping you in
different particular areas like BMAD
method which is uh AIdriven agile
development that is going to help you
with software and game development and
it will automatically adapt from a
single bug fix to enterprise scale
systems. You also have other methods
like BMAD builder which is BMBB and it
is to create custom solutions where you
can create your own agents workflows and
modules. All of this is essentially
integrated within the BMAD core and you
can use these different modules in
different ways cuz it's modular. To get
started, it is really simple. Just make
sure you have Node.js 20 and above. And
once you have Node.js installed, you can
simply head over to the GitHub
repository, which I'll leave a link to
in the description below. And if you're
using version 6 alpha, you want to use
the npxbad method install, which is
recommended for new projects. And if
you're working with production, you can
use the following install command. I can
open up my command prompt and simply go
ahead and paste this in. And this will
install the BMAD core onto my computer.
Before we get started, I just want to
mention that you should definitely go
ahead and subscribe to the World of AI
newsletter. I'm constantly posting
different newsletters on a weekly basis.
So this is where you can easily get
up-to-date knowledge about what is
happening in the AI space. So definitely
go ahead and subscribe as this is
completely for free. After it finishes
installing, you can run the installer
and choose which module you want to
install. So in this case, it will ask
you a couple settings. You'll want to
set the installation directory. I have
set it to a new directory called AI
agent. And within that directory, it's
going to ask for a couple questions like
what's your name, what language as well
as option that you want to use. And then
you can select the BMAD modules that you
want to install. You can install all of
them, but you want to install the one
that makes most sense for that
particular project. And you can read
through which module works best for the
your project. So if you're working to
build your own custom agent, you can use
BMBB. you want to use the other one
which is the BMM method which is the
AIdriven agile development method that I
would recommend that you use I would
select this option but if you want to
use all of them you can definitely do
that as well I believe the BMM method is
going to be the best for this particular
use case so I can click enter next is
where it's going to ask us which tools
you want to integrate the BMAD method
with you can choose any of these
afterwards as well but in this case I'm
going to be using it with Kilo code
because I believe that is the best for
AI code development. So I will select
that and I can give it a title of my
project that I'm working on.
Now it will showcase that BMAD is ready
to use cuz it has finished installing
within that directory. Now all you got
to do is use the initialization command
and you can get started with BMAD. To
get started now head over to VS Code,
your IDE. You can use whatever ID you
want, but I'm using VS Code cuz it's
free. And then you can go ahead and open
up your AI coding agent. I'm using Kilo
code because it is the best AI coding
agent that's available that's open
source. You can install it by heading
over to the extension store, going over
to kilo code by searching it up and then
installing it and you will be able to
access it on the left hand side. You
also have it so that you can access the
APIs completely for free because they
give you $25 worth of free credits. But
now what we can do is select pod because
I believe this is the best model for
spec development. And then we can go
ahead and have it open up the AI Asian
directory or wherever you had simply
installed the BMAD method. So I've
opened up the directory where I
installed BMAD and you can see that the
presets are ready to be configured. All
I got to do now is go to my kilo code AI
agent and I can simply go ahead and run
the workflow initialization command
which is where it is going to tell the
AI agent to initiate the workflow that
BMAD has set and it will set up the base
structure of our project. And you can
see that the AI agent is intelligent
enough to read through all the files
before it initiates it. And you can see
that now it is going to configure the
yam file and it will initialize the BMAD
method workflow tracking system.
And you can now see that kilo code the
AI agent is working with BMAD to now set
up our project. It is asking if the
project name is correct which it is. And
now it is going to ask us a couple of
specifications on what we want the
project to accomplish. This is because
we have selected the BMAD quick spec
flow method which is the base structure
with the BMBB method. And now what we
can do is we can simply have it
requested to solve different sorts of
bug fixes. We can have it rapidly
prototype or have it just work on quick
enhancements. And the flow is pretty
easy. It starts off by running this tech
spec workflow. It detects project stack.
It's going to understand your overall
workflow which is really important cuz
you want to make sure that the AI Asia
has a full contextual awareness of every
component of your project before making
any sort of change and then it will
analyze any component that is needed
generate the contextrich text spec and
then it will create a ready to go
implement story. Now the second step is
optional but you can either have it so
that you can start brainstorming,
researching or do both of that. But
since I already have completed that
task, we can then continue forward and
have it implement the dev agent which
will code test and commit and it will
accomplish this task with the specd
driven components. And what I like about
kilo code working with vad is that it
will help you choose the right option
where it'll give you a good idea of what
it should work on the honest
recommendation for for your AI agent. It
recommends the BMAD method which is
option two which is with full planning.
So I can go ahead and select this. But
if you want to use the quick flow method
which is fast with minimal planning, you
can also select this. And now it looks
like it is taking in my prompt to create
a web scraping AI agent. This is what I
specified within the YAM file. And now
after I provided my text specs, it is
going to deploy to the different
engineering team members to execute it.
This is how basically it works. It is
where it deploys these different tasks
to different agents with this detailed
plan so that it makes sure that the
context is basically thoroughly infused
at each step of the production and
you'll be able to get a better unified
generation thanks to BMAD with this
thought process. And it's not even that
expensive. It is something that might be
a little bit more expensive than having
it generated with individual steps, but
that is better than having it repeat
multiple steps over and over again by
the AI agent.
And just take a look at the quality of
output of BMAD. This is where I simply
just requested to create an AI scraping
agent. And you can see the
implementation plan that it has
developed where it is going to basically
develop all these components one by one
where one component might be focused on
the scraper component of the agent which
is a robust HTTP scraper that can
scratch and fetch static web pages. It
is where it has detailed all the
components that it will implement for
that specific feature. In the same way,
there's also a data export feature and
other components that it has fully
developed. This is something that will
help have the AI agent retain memory
across all of the generations and it
will make sure that it will 100% kod all
of these functions for you. So rather
than just sending a single prompt to an
AI agent which might not actually
deliver on all the components or is
lackluster with certain components, this
is where it will properly generate
everything one by one like the static
page scraping capability, the CLI
interface and so many more. Now what we
can do is tell the AI coding agent to
work on start building all of these
components out. And you can see the
project is fully developed. Now the
implementation of the CLI interface has
been complete. It has even debugged it
and tested it out on its own thanks to
the Kilo code agent. And now what we got
to do is just install the dependencies.
And we can paste this in which will
install the AI agent. And then we can
run the scraper by using the Python
command and then pasting in the URL to
execute any task. So, I just told the AI
agent to scrape the world of AI
newsletter. And it's going to scrape all
the components off this website and
paste it into another file, whether
that's marked on or JSON. And just take
a look at that. It has finished scraping
the contents off of the world of AI
website based off the AI agent that the
BMAD method had developed with kilo
code. And you can see all the components
of what it had extracted, the text, the
URL, all of it has been outputed into
this JSON file. This is something that I
developed in less than two minutes and
it took approximately $2 to fully
compose all the components that we had
requested. It had made sure that there
is the HTML scraping feature, data
extraction, and then all the other
components like we had requested. If you
like this video and would love to
support the channel, you can consider
donating to my channel through the super
thanks option below. Or you can consider
joining our private Discord where you
can access multiple subscriptions to
different AI tools for free on a monthly
basis, plus daily AI news and exclusive
content, plus a lot more. To be honest,
for me to explain all the components and
modules, I would need a fullon hour
lesson to showcase everything. But
that's basically just a rough outline of
the BMAD core method. It is something
that I highly recommend that you use. It
is similar to the other components that
we have showcased on this channel. But
this is something that is the original
one that is best with the main
philosophy of specdriven development.
And I'll leave all these links in the
description below so that you can get
started. But with that thought guys,
thank you guys so much for watching.
Subscribe to the second channel, join
the newsletter, join our private
Discord, follow me on Twitter. Lastly,
make sure you guys subscribe, turn on
notification bell, like this video, and
please take a look at our previous
videos because there's a lot of content
that you'll truly benefit from. But with
that thought, guys, have an amazing day.
Spread positivity, and I'll see you guys
really shortly. Peace out.